<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.gnome.dataguardian</id>
  <license>GPL-3.0-only</license>
  <name>Data Guardian</name>
  <summary>Your personal, vigilant backup assistant for Linux desktops</summary>

  <developer_name>Geovane Jefferson</developer_name>

  <description>
    <p>
      Data Guardian is a powerful Python-based backup solution designed to keep your important files, settings, and applications safe with minimal effort. It combines an intelligent daemon, a modern GTK4-based GUI, and advanced backup strategies to deliver a seamless, reliable data protection experience.
    </p>
    <p>Key Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Automatic &amp; Incremental Backups: Effortless, continuous protection with intelligent versioning.</li>
      <li>Smart &amp; Selective Backup: Configure exclusions for directories, file types, or hidden files.</li>
      <li>External Drive Integration: Detects and backs up to your selected external storage.</li>
      <li>Robust Backup Integrity: Uses SHA-256 hashing, size, and modification time checks. Resilient to interruptions.</li>
      <li>Comprehensive Application Backup: Saves a list of installed Flatpak applications.</li>
      <li>Modern, User-Friendly GUI: Built with GTK4 and Libadwaita for intuitive control.</li>
      <li>Resilient &amp; Configurable Daemon: Handles signals, device changes, and offers detailed logging.</li>
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.gnome.dataguardian.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="cached">com.gnome.dataguardian</icon>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GeovaneJefferson/dataguardian/main/data/screenshoot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://geovanejefferson.github.io/dataguardian/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/GeovaneJefferson/dataguardian/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.patreon.com/GeovaneJefferson</url>

  <provides>
    <binary>dataguardian</binary>
  </provides>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>System</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>backup</keyword>
    <keyword>restore</keyword>
    <keyword>files</keyword>
    <keyword>synchronization</keyword>
    <keyword>versioning</keyword>
    <keyword>automation</keyword>
    <keyword>linux</keyword>
    <keyword>gtk</keyword>
    <keyword>libadwaita</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1 dev" date="2024-07-20">
      <description>
        <p>Initial development release. Under active development, use with caution.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating />

</component>